alitools.io 2019-06-05

# Privacy Policy — AliTools

### Introduction

Friends, we the developers want to be open and tell you about our AliTools service and how it works. We sincerely believe in our product and in the good it can do for society. From us you'll find out just what data our service collects, how we use your data, and whether there are any risks for the user. If you still have any questions or comments after you've read this document, we're always happy to hear them by mail: [privacy@alitools.io](mailto:privacy@alitools.io).

Privacy policy regarding personal data

### Privacy Policy

This privacy policy governs your use of software products (hereinafter the Service) developed by Big Data Technologies Ltd (hereinafter AliTools or We). The Service currently includes:

  * AliTools (hereinafter the extension) for web browsers on desktop personal computers;
  * AliTools (Android and iOS apps) for mobile devices ;
  * the AliTools.io website (available at <http://alitools.io/>).

We have developed these products in order to help our users to save time and money efficiently while choosing products on websites that interest them.

### What information does the service receive, and how can it be used?

#### Information provided by the user

The service obtains information from users immediately after they sign up. Signing up is not mandatory, but it is required for users to access the full functionality of the service.

When signup is necessary to use particular features, you will be invited to log in or else to sign up for the service if you have not yet done so.

When you sign up with us to use the service, we usually ask you you provide your name, e-mail address, a username, a password and some other information necessary for registration. If we need information from you while you are using the service, we will ask for that additional information and explain why we need it. In addition, when you contact us for help and enter information about your problem, we automatically save the data to enable us to provide adequate assistance in solving the problem.

#### Information collected automatically

To make the service and its main functions reliably available for use, we gather certain information automatically: the type of device you are using, a unique identifier for your device, the IP address of your device, the operating system you are using, the type of browser used, the websites that you visit using our service, non-personal data that is retrieved from the websites you visit, as well as data about how you use the service when interacting with it on the websites you visit. Other information connected to your use of the service may also be collected.

Wherever possible, we give you the option of choosing in your user settings what information you are happy to provide to the service and what information to prefer to keep inaccessible.

### What information we do not acquire?

The privacy and security of your data are very important to us. There are many types of information that our service does not receive or collect. For example, we do not collect any information from your e-mail, your credit card or your bank accounts. We do not record personal information you have not provided to us, directly or indirectly, unless we have received permission to use this information.

We adhere to the following rule: the service runs in the browser extension only on trusted sites, where there is no fear of leakage of users' personal data.

### Do third parties see information received by the service, or have access to it?

We will transfer this information to third parties only in cases described in this privacy policy.

We may disclose information provided by a user or collected automatically:

  * in accordance with the requirements of the law on subpoena or similar legal process;
  * when we sincerely believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or protect your safety or the safety of other users, or when investigating fraud or in response to a request from the Government;
  * to our trusted service providers who work on our behalf, but may not be able to use information provided independently to them, and who have agreed with us that they will abide by the rules set out in this privacy policy;
  * if we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or assets sale in whole or in part, you will be notified of any change in ownership or use of this information via email or through a prominent announcement on our website . We will always provide you with a choice. For example, you can refuse to provide your personal data to the service by fully and permanently deleting your account;
  * in conjunction with other data so that personal information is not disclosed, but the data is anonymized.

### What are my Opt-out rights?

You can stop our service collecting information from you by simply deleting your account and no longer visiting our website. Deleting an account takes place according to the standard features used by users of web browsers or mobile devices.

So you can control your personal information, we give you the opportunity to make changes in the settings of the account you hold with the service. Remember that making changes can involve blocking some important features.

### Data retention and information management policies

We store user data and collect information about you automatically while you use our service. If you want us to delete your account and all data you have provided about yourself. please contact us at [privacy@alitools.io](mailto:privacy@alitools.io) and we will respond within 96 hours. Note that only data you have provided will be deleted. Automatically collected data cannot be deleted, because they are part of the service and are necessary to keep all our services functioning properly.

### Cookies

We use cookies as well as other semi-permanent markers to identify users of the service. When you sign up as a user and create an account, your account is linked to the service's identification markers and synced with them. Your consent to the use of identifiers is needed to limit fraudulent and abusive use of our services.

### Children

We do not collect data or use services that are forbidden to children aged under 13 years. If parents or guardians become aware that a child has provided information to us without consent from adults, they should contact us at [privacy@alitools.io](mailto:privacy@alitools.io). We will delete the information from our databases within 96 hours. 

### Security

We care about protecting your information and keeping it private. We restrict access to information to our authorized employees and contractors who need to know such data in order to operate, develop and improve our service. Note that although we strive to maintain and ensure the safety of your personal information, no system can prevent violation of safety rules with absolute certainty.

### Changes

This privacy policy may be updated from time to time. We will notify you in a timely manner of any changes to our privacy policy by posting updates on this page. It is recommended that you regularly consult our privacy policy and check the date of its renewal. Your continued use of our services constitutes your acceptance of the privacy policy. If you are dissatisfied for any reason, you can write to us at [privacy@alitools.io](mailto:privacy@alitools.io) and we will reply to you within 96 hours.

### Your consent

By using the service, you consent to the processing of your information as described in this privacy policy, and you also agree to our amendments. "Processing" means using cookies on your computer or portable device, collecting, storing, deleting, using, combining and disclosing information. All work with data may be conducted in any country of the world, because our offices are located in different countries around the world.

### Contact us

If you have any questions relating to protecting your privacy while using the service, or if you have questions about our work, please contact us by email at [privacy@alitools.io](mailto:privacy@alitools.io). We will respond to you within 96 hours. Thank you.
